Jiajun Wu

Personal website: https://wujiajunic.cn/

Email: jjwu@connect.hku.hk

Address: CB, Main Campus, HKU, Hong Kong GitHub: https://github.com/MaxwellWjj

Jiajun Wu is currently a PhD student in the Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE), the University of Hong Kong (HKU). His research interests include FPGA system, hardware accelerators, neuromorphic computing, and computer architecture.



EDUCATION =

THE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

Hong Kong

PhD Student in Electrical and Electronic Engineering, from 09/2021 to present

Supervisor: Prof. Hayden Kwok-Hay So

Current Research Topics:

- AI Hardware Accelerator

- Computer Architecture

HUAZHONG UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

("Double First-Class" initiative, "985" Project)

Wuhan, China

Bachelor in IC Design and Integrated System, from 09/2017 to 06/2021 GPA 3.89/4.0

Supervisor: Prof. Chao Wang Representative Courses:

- CMOS Analog Integrated Circuit

- Fundamentals of Digital Integrated Circuit

- Hardware Description Language and Design of Digital System

- Processor Architecture
- Principles of Embedded System
- Principles of Computer Architecture

EXCHANGE & INTERNSHIP

SINGAPORE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AND DESIGN

Singapore

Internship, from 15/01/2020 to 03/02/2020

Supervised by Prof. Shaowei Lin, Singapore University of Technology and Design

Project: Study of Advanced Algorithms of Neuromorphic Computing and Hardware Implementation

ZHUHAI UM SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY RESEARCH INSTITUTE / UNIVERSITY OF MACAU

Zhuhai, China

Internship, from 28/07/2020 to 31/10/2020

Supervised by Prof. Sai Weng Sin, University of Macau

Project: Study of 3D ToF sensor based advanced mixed-signal circuit design

PUBLICATIONS

- **J. Wu** *et al.*, "An Energy-Efficient GALS Multi-core Restricted Boltzmann Machine Processor with On-chip Bi-plausible Learning and Reconfigurable Sparsity", in *IEEE A-SSCC 2020*, Nov. 2020.
- **J.** Wu¹, Y. Zhan¹ *et al.*, "Efficient Design of Spiking Neural Network With STDP Learning Based on Fast CORDIC," in *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems I: Regular Papers*, vol. 68, no. 6, pp. 2522-2534, June 2021.
- **J. Wu** *et al.*, "An Energy-efficient Deep Belief Network Processor Based on Heterogeneous Multi-core Architecture with Transposable Memory and On-chip Learning," in *IEEE JETCAS*, under review.
- J. Xu, Y. Zhan, Y. Li, **J. Wu**, X. Ji, G. Yu, W. Jiang, R. Zhao and C. Wang, "In-Situ Aging-aware Error Monitoring Scheme for IMPLY-based Memristive Computing-in-Memory Systems," in *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems I: Regular Papers*, in press, 2021.
- Q. Wang, Y. Zhan, B. Liu, **J. Wu**, Y. Shi, G. Yu, and C. Wang, "A Reconfigurable Area and Energy Efficient Hardware Accelerator of Five High-order Operators for Vision Sensor Based Robot Systems," in *Proc. of IEEE International Conference on Integrated Circuits, Technologies and Applications* (ICTA 2021), Nov. 24-26, 2021.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

-

¹ Equally contributed to this work

STUDY OF TOF ALGORITHM BASED ADVANCED MIXED-SIGNAL CIS DESIGN

Adviser: Prof. Sai Weng Sin Institution: Singapore University of Technology and Design

Zhuhai, China July 2020 - present

• The project is still going on. We are studying advanced recognition / classification algorithm based on Time-of-Flight (ToF) sensors and 3D images. Then, we look forward to implementing some energy-efficient accelerator such as NN accelerator, and finally getting a chip design.

STUDY OF NEURAL NETWORK BASED NEUROMORPHIC COMPUTING AND HIGH ENERGY EFFICIENT CHIP DESIGN

Wuhan, China

Adviser: Prof. Chao Wang Institution: Research Lab of Ultra Low-Power and Intelligent Integrated Circuits present

May 2019 -

Proposed a reconfigurable and highly efficient Spiking Neural Network (SNN) based on fast-convergence COordinate
Rotation DIgital Computer (CORDIC) algorithm is proposed to achieve digital hardware implementation. This work
has been summarized into a paper and under review.

STUDY OF ADVANCED ALGORITHMS OF NEUROMORPHIC COMPUTING AND HARDWARE IMPLEMENTATION

Singapore

Adviser: Prof. Shaowei Lin

Institution: Singapore University of Technology and Design

Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

• Joined the development of VPF and MPN source code and understood its mathematical significance deeply. Implemented basic modules of VPF algorithm's hardware accelerator and verified in RTL simulation level.

HIGH RELIABILITY LITHIUM BATTERY SYSTEM WITH INTEGRATED ULTRASONIC SENSOR NETWORK Wuha

Wuhan, China

Adviser: Prof. Yue Shen

Institution: HUST-WISCO Joint Laboratory

Feb 2019 - May 2019

• Integrated the ultrasonic sensor network into the battery module, using the ultrasonic signal to monitor the state of the battery, obtaining a high-precision state of charge and health, especially the battery gas detection limit is as low as 20 uL, far beyond traditional technology.

COMPETITION AWARDS² =

FIRST PRIZE IN TI CUP COLLEGE STUDENTS' ELECTRONIC DESIGN COMPETITION

Institution: Science & Technology Innovation Center, HUST

Aug 2018

SECOND PRIZE IN CHALLENGE CUP HUBEI PROVINCE COLLEGE STUDENTS' EXTRACURRICULAR ACADEMIC SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY WORKS CONTEST

Institution: School of Artificial Intelligence and Automation, HUST

Mar 2019 - May 2019

SECOND PRIZE IN CHINA UNIVERSITY INTELLIGENT ROBOT CREATIVE COMPETITION

Institution: School of Artificial Intelligence and Automation, HUST

Mar 2019 - May 2019

SKILLS

C/C++ Python FPGA MATLAB Verilog-HDL Embedded System

- Developed small software apps based on some desktop platforms (e.g., Qt).
- Developed some software-hardware co-design implementations on FPGA, especially with Xilinx devices.
- ALL the source codes of my publications and other works are shared in my GitHub: https://github.com/MaxwellWjj

2 --

² Only national or provincial high-level competition awards are listed here.